Lesson 12 Banks and their customers
银行和顾客
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
Why is there no risk to the customer when a bank prints the customer's name on his cheques?
为什么说,银行把储户姓名印在其支票上对储户来说毫无风险?
account: n.  账户
When anyone opens a current account at a bank,he is lending the bank money.
任何人在银行开一个活期帐户,就等于把钱借给了银行.
repayment of which he may demand at any time
这笔钱他可以随时提取,
cash: n.  现金
either in cash or by drawing a cheque in favour of another person.
提取的方式可以是取现金,也可以是开一张以他人为收款人的支票.
debtor: n.  借方, creditor: n.  贷方
Primarily,the banker- customer relationship is that of debtor and creditor--
银行与储户的关系主要是债务人和债权人的关系.
account: n.  账户
who is which depending on whether the custom- er's account is in credit or is overdrawn
究竟谁是债务人谁是债权人,要看储户的账户是有结余还是透支.
But,in addition to that basically simple concept,
除了这一基本的简单的概念外,
obligation: n.  义务
the bank and its customer owe a large number of obligations to one another.
银行和储户彼此还需承担大量义务.
obligation: n.  义务, complication: n.  纠纷
Many of these obligations can give rise to problems and complications
其中许多义务往往引起问题和纠纷.
but a bank customer, unlike,say,a buyer of goods,
但是储户不能像货物的买主那样，aa
cannot complain that the law is loaded against him.
来抱怨法律对自己不利.
The bank must obey its customer's instructions,and not those of anyone else.
银行必须遵照储户的嘱托办事,不能听从其他人的指令.
account: n.  账户, debit: v.  把...记入借方
When,for example,a customer first opens an account, he instructs the bank to debit his account only in respect of cheques drawn by himself.
比如,储户首次在银行开户时,嘱咐银行，他的存款只能凭他本人签字的支票来提取。
specimen: n.  样本
He gives the bank specimens of his signature,and there is a very firm rule
他把自己签名的样本交给银行,对此有一条非常严格的规定:
that the bank has no right or authority to pay out a customer's money on a cheque,
银行没有任何权利或理由把储户的钱，
forge: v.  伪造
on which its customer's signature has been forged.
让伪造储户签名的支票取走.
forge: v.  伪造, forgery: n.  伪造（文件，签名等）
It makes no difference that the forgery may have been a very skillful one:
即使伪造得很巧妙,也不能付款,
the bank must recognize its customer's signature.
因为银行有责任辨认出其储户的签名.
adopt: v.  采用
For this reason there is no risk to the cus- tomer in the practice, adopted by banks,
因此,在下述银行贯例作法中,储户不会有任何风险,即:
of printing the customer's name on his cheques.
把储户姓名印在支票上.
forge: v.  伪造, forgery: n.  伪造（文件，签名等）, facilitate: v.  使便利
If this facilitates forgery,it is the bank which will lose, not the customer.
如果因这种作法出现了伪造的话,受损失的将不是储户,而是银行.